

Rutuja Joshi COUNSELLING PSYCHOLOGIST

PROFILE

Passionate about psychology and mental health. Dedicated to creating mental health awareness and reaching out to maximum individuals, groups and communities for the same.

Ardent reader. Passionate dancer. Loves to write.

Experience as a Counselling Psychologist and Subject Matter Expert. Registered as a Therapist with My Fit Brain and as a Career Counsellor with Career Guide.

Also worked as a Dance trainer: and English and French tutor.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Birth date

28-01-1997

Nationality

Indian

Address

H/101, Srirasi, Panchajanya CHS, Behind Apla Bazaar, Ramchandra Nagar, Near Icon Hospital, Manpada Road, Dombivli East, 421201.

CONTACT

- rutuja.joshi1000@gmail.com
- 9930255838
- https://rutujoshi.wordpress.com

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

ONLINE PSYCHOLOGY EXPERT

May 2020 EVELYN LEARNING SYSTEMS

Creating answers for chapter-end and test-bank questions.

SUBJECT MATTER EXPERT

M AND R CONSULTANTS CORPORATION, THANE February 2020 - March 2020 Accuracy check of e-learning material of Biological Psychology.

COUNSELLING PSYCHOLOGIST

MAHARSHI DAYANAND COLLEGE, PAREL

July 2019 - April 2020

- 1. Conducting counselling sessions for junior and senior college students for emotional, behavioral, family, relationship and career related problems.
- 2. Conducting mental health and life skills related workshops for students.

COUNSELLING PSYCHOLOGIST

DNYANESHWARI SCHOOL, DOMBIVLI

July 2019 - April 2020

- 1. Conducting counselling sessions for primary and secondary school students for academic, emotional, behavioral and family related problems.
- 2. Conducting mental health awareness workshops for teachers.

EDUCATION

Post Graduate Diploma in Sports Psychology

SMT. MANIBN M. P. SHAH WOMEN'S COLLEGE OF ARTS AND COMMERCE, MATUNGA

April 2019

April 2019

April 2017

March 2014

MA in Counselling Psychology

SMT. MANIBEN M. P. SHAH WOMEN'S COLLEGE OF ARTS AND COMMERCE, MATUNGA, SNDT WOMEN'S UNIVERSITY

BA in Psychology

K. C. COLLEGE, CHURCHGATE, MUMBAI UNIVERSITY

HSC (Arts) Maharashtra Board

V. G. VAZE (KELKAR) COLLEGE OF ARTS, SCIENCE AND COMMERCE, MULUND

SSC Maharashtra Board

VIDYA NIKETAN SCHOOL, DOMBIVLI March 2012

COUNSELLING AND TEACHING SKILLS



Observation and Empathy



MS office

OTHER SKILLS



Listening and Communication

Writing and Content Development

LANGUAGES

English Marathi Hindi

CERTIFICATIONS

- Counselling and Psychological Assessment
- **Honours Certificate**
- Career Counselling
- **CERT Course for Guiding School Students**

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Reading, Writing, Dance, Anchoring

French